all right so we are still figuring out
what we're gonna do for the next hour
because what we had planned doesn't work
with the lack of participation in the
way that we need it to be to host an
hour that we had to had plans during
this time so we're figuring something
also so we are joined by Sam who has a
project called born at home is that
right dot yeah bought a home dog all
right so can you tell us about the
project what it is so basically it's
introducing people to the game V space
in a I don't know if it you'd say the
game B space but just more of a civic
civically minded oriented space and
trying to do that in a in a way that is
accessible makes makes the whole thing
more easily approachable to people
without using you know the term game B
for example and I suppose it the idea is
kind of it's come from a few different
things and now obviously with the
coronavirus it's kind of this board at
home thing seems to fit and I've just
decided to go with that because I'm
quite indecisive anyway but so yeah it's
I'm kind of I feel like it's an open
source thing I don't really feel like
it's my project I'm open to anyone
else's thought so I've got like a
general vision but yeah I'm sure you
want to share your yes so basically
thinking a website which will introduce
the ideas in basic terms and then kind
of say well we're all kind of bored
and we got problems so so and he is here
all the things that we've got there are
fingertips to tell help solve them you
know which I think so in some ways it's
to inspire people at first and then it
will lead into essentially a lead into
actions that people can do one of them
would be choice I'll start with myself
so they could be be given two options
once they've been inspired assuming that
you know they do feel inspired they're
on the website itself they'll be given
the option to start with themselves so
that would lead into possible you know
just things that help us do things
better generally I had a few things I
thought of like yoga and meditation
especially with people being bored it
may help them deal with it but obviously
that helps with our thinking and
everything so that would be the more the
personal option and then the second
option which is really the main one
would be leading people to so I've got
the design up here and it says I want to
connect with others and then that would
lead people to an overview of the kind
of ecosystem of game B so I actually
imagined it as having a you'd be able to
choose the category of because I think
everyone's different everyone's
interested in different things like just
as individuals would some people are
quite Liberty minded and other people
are more concerned about the environment
and so I thought that they would be able
to click what they were interested in
and then it would show them the groups
that kind of came came under that
general category and then obviously that
that will lead them to say wherever that
particular group is based on online so
maybe the face
expert group or it may be telegram or
you know anywhere where the kind of
locus of communication is happening so
yeah I don't know if that makes sense
you have any questions about that no no
questions about um I was more taking
notes on what you were saying rather
than generating questions at that exact
moment
hey troll do you have any questions um
no questions I do like the approach of
like not just saying here's what what
work needs to be done but also the
lights you know I guess the easier like
here's other stuff that you can do at
home so it becomes just you know a home
page for things to do when you're bored
at home and one of those things might be
helping with game view projects I do
yeah I like that approach as well I like
the idea of having options for people to
work on themselves and having people
work on tasks whether that's the one-off
tasks or projects in in general and
being able to guide people towards it
that is similar to ideas I think we have
been working out or at least I've been
working on is like how to bring people
together and how the communication piece
I would love to hear more about how far
you are on it and what you need for it
to be moving forward yeah I think I've
I've been worried that I'd lose focus so
I'm just trying to get maybe not
everything into the first iteration of
it I did think that so it would lead
people to the categories of the
different projects which could be an
idea or it could actually be an actual
project where people are looking for
people to help with it that kind of
splits off into potentially adding like
a job listing section
so obviously you can drill down further
into into the thing but to start with
that I'm basically are probably not too
far off on having built the websites I
suppose and I need sorry be able to go
to it and use it
sorry did you say when yeah um well us
hoping actually by the end of next week
in its kind of simplify simple format
and then obviously can but in terms of
things are need I I think I asked if
anyone had any projects open and I
basically I have a few ideas for
projects myself but I thought it could
be like an idea repository as well as
acting is a kind of channeling people
through to these communities because
often ideas get lost don't they so yeah
I don't know like I'm getting off track
well squish yeah I don't know cuz I did
not write it down oh that's fine it was
when when we can use it and you said
you'd answered it it was a week yeah
sorry sorry
yeah it's obviously the game B section
with the categories and entries of
projects doesn't have there's nothing
there so I need to create a like a
little database or just a spreadsheet of
the
the currently open projects and
obviously there may be projects out
there that aren't within our kind of
sphere of perception I'm kind of new to
this game be space so I'm poor I'm not
too familiar with some of your guys
projects but they sound really good
actually but I'm not yeah I'm I haven't
been looking so we have projects that
like I said we keep talking about them
like we're just trying to figure it out
for r3 which doesn't work we need other
people's but I forgot that maybe you
didn't know what those were we just want
to give a like one minute overview do
you want to hear one minute overview of
what our projects are some yeah that'd
be great yeah all right who wants to
start Bentley you know what oh I think
you're hard needed sounds not working
you can't hear you
so all that figures out Israel you go
first all right sure so my project is
called wiki electioned it is like that
the main goal is to fight misinformation
and it does that by focusing on the
evidence available for things like
politics science and news all right and
I don't think I can go a layer deeper
without talking about it four minutes
huh hello yeah that sounds good jibley
Jana my project my current project is
solution raising so I have had six
conversations on various sectors of the
world and with with other people within
an hour come up with a potential
adjacent solution we could accomplish if
we had right now if we had 10,000 people
and $100,000 and so we've come up with
like ones for transportation and food
and education and they're all
things that are absolutely possible
right now if we actually had 10,000
people under $1000 and so now I'm
looking at how do we actually create
that how do we bring 10,000 people
together or how do we start to build
towards that and how do we start to
build towards finding funding yeah
that's great
okay can you all hear me now yeah yeah
we can hear you how about yours
so my project is reason to score it's
very similar to aid riyals and actually
it would kind of be a feature of his
site and similar sites where it's a
place that people can discuss
contentious issues and instead of
exploring for opinions that kind of
helps people explore and categorize the
the facts and the information and then
it kind of it tracks a score so that
people can make sense of a lot of
information much more quickly than
having to read at all so that's the idea
yeah that sounds great
glad you sir asked because obviously
with this project that I'm looking at
its obviously but is there anything you
are you guys interested in having more
people to talk about these your projects
and you know bounce ideas around or is
it is there something else that you're
you need for your respective projects I
mean I need other people to co-create
what ten thousand people and a hundred
thousand dollars looks like and
participate in this solution raising and
participating making improving the
solution raising together how do we have
an hour-long conversation that people
want to be part of and generates an idea
and then how do we actually move that
idea towards existing in the real world
and that stuff that I think we need to
come up with together which means we
need it together we need people who are
invested in it
yeah and for my part I it's always good
to have more kind of people involved
I'm sure I'd ruin our both use more
developers and but also just people who
would be willing to try a beta tool and
give feedback and participate in its and
its development by ideas and and just
giving feedback and actual users will
always be helpful I'm not quite there
yet but will be soon so and yeah and
then you know we're all passionate about
this area so we enjoy helping each other
out and other projects so that would be
in you know jubblies project we enjoy
participating in that do you have a
project you want to tell us about um I
probably think I don't really have a
project right now I'm trying to have a
vision of a different social structure
than we are living under right now but
it does seem to involve all of your
different projects so I'm curious still
learning what you're all doing
supportive I might have a project that I
it's on the backburner to them we'll
talk about it if I guiltless hi everyone
nice to meet you hi alright so we've
talked about Sam's idea for his project
and we kind of turn this into a bit of a
project raising however now that there's
five of us I have a question which is
this time this nine o'clock in the
morning is a time that we had kind of
set aside for figuring out the meta
project right like how we actually
create something together that
facilitates
all of our projects is that something
that people would be interested in is
meeting during this time and having a
type of mastermind group or co-creating
what that looks like what would be the
most powerful thing to move our projects
forward as the steward of that project
right as the person who can get help
from other people but like you're the
one taking that on and how do we find
other people to hopefully in my case
anyway I want other people participating
in creating it together
like how we how we get together and
brainstorm solutions to the like the
next thing we have a problem - problem
with right now does that make sense are
you asking is that how we want to use
this time today or in general
well sadly all of the above
holiday bug is yeah because if we have
people even five people and meeting and
talking about their project and the
pitfalls and how we co-create solutions
together I think we are getting value
out of it and the audience might also be
getting value out of it in that they
might be able to find projects they
might be the people right who come to
whatever we create and they might have
projects themselves and want to
participate in it and can brainstorm
ideas of how to improve this process
right how to brainstorm with the
audience how to I don't know many many
options yeah I like I like using this
time for that both is like a kind of a
mastermind group if people are familiar
with that term and also just kind of
point out something you've already
thought about - was it what adds Sam's
describing his project that's very
similar to what we have already kind of
been discussing a central repository for
the four projects and how people can
help and stuff so yeah I think it could
be both and all day about I think what
we might help because we've tried to go
through a few different iterations of oh
hey let's try this and then we show up
and there's no there's not enough people
there's not enough interest to actually
do that thing I almost wonder if we want
like a I don't know
hello chart for lack of a better term
that says you know here's the things
that we can use the session for and we
have our ideal spot where said if we get
you know five or six people and they
have projects and all the stuff then we
do this kind of a session we don't have
you know quorum for that then you go
into a smaller session and so it's sort
of a consecutively smaller group of
thing
we're in the end yeah you know the
people who show up regularly if it's
just me Jubilee and Bentley then that's
a certain kind of a meeting where maybe
it's not our favorite but we can do it
anyway and then as more people show up
there's different sort of checkboxes oh
look we have enough people to do this
thing
let's have that kind of a session
instead or we figure out what I was is
there are five of us if this time works
for us how do we co-create this hour for
the next three weeks or the next if it's
every other week you know any next every
other week for three weeks six weeks
whatever that how do we want to
participate in this how would it give us
the most benefit as project folders to
create something won't want to be a part
of right what would that mastermind look
like so we want to show up and be part
of it and help our own project but also
help other people's right like there's
not a project here that I don't think
would be of benefit to the world and I
want to help get out into the world
right so how do we create it for to work
for our selves our projects and the meta
project what does this hour look like
that you would want to continue to come
back for I suppose every I've just kind
of learnt about your guys ideas and over
the next week I'll probably eww a few
connections that happen in my brain and
you know I'm sure it's the same for
everyone else so maybe just two I like
you say brainstorm but maybe there's a
bit more see what happens kind of aspect
to it I don't know
so the format that I kind of like is is
kind of the standard mastermind format
where it's you know we can all give a
one or two minute update of what we
progressed on in the last week and then
one person can say I you know I have a
problem and then we all kind of
brainstorm helping that into the Joe on
that problem and oftentimes the problems
are shared so working through someone's
problem would help ours so I guess I'd
like to throw that out as a format to
start with or other ideas sounds kind of
perfect for a project I didn't actually
heard the mastermind group like
explained in sort of a short form that
help so yeah that sounds awesome
different formats that's that's the
heart that's the hotseat format is that
something that Shiloh what do you think
and Sam what do you think or how that
looks do you want to add to it or um
that sounds really good actually
but Bentley said yeah how you summarize
it all right we can try it out yeah the
one thing I also want to to mention is
kind of excited the fact that we have
someone here who doesn't really have
like a project explicitly cuz we've been
trying to to get someone to kind of play
the like project volunteer side to say
like what would it take to get you
involved in a project what would it
because I would help with the project
but it's not my focus my focus is you
know actually working on the projects
that have already done so I think it's
harder for me to put myself in the shoes
of somebody that might go to abort at
home or or eight together tech and say
you know I'm bored at home I want some
work to do what what can I help with and
so that's something that I think it's
important that is sort of in there as
well even if the person who's acting is
the volunteer might not give our project
update if they might have a different
role in there but I think it's important
to have them involved at every step and
to sort of make sure that they're baked
into that approach because I think
that's half the battle
like I know Julie and I on soon Sam one
of her ongoing things that we need is an
audience is people you know
to BOPE just show up and show interest
but also to actually help out because uh
unlike that me I have it's tech thing
and I'm not a coder even so it's I
really do help yeah and yeah on that on
that point I am also working with some
startups in the area I'm mentoring four
or five of them and there are mostly
non-technical founders so we might start
spending some time on finding reliable
resources for low-cost development
because there's a lot out there but a
lot of it I've heard lots and lots of
horror stories so that may be one
project I'm going to be working on soon
I really don't want to spend time on it
but there's such a need of non-technical
founders of being able to vet technical
resources now many of us don't have the
the funding and our projects to do that
but for those that do it might be
helpful so is that just so I'm sort of
aware uh
I like back-end is that more like if
you're a non-technical founder and you
need to work done the kind of like the
kind of questions you might ask on a
site like up work yeah yeah kind of how
to protect yourself in those situations
how to handle that project but also I'm
hoping we'll actually have some vendors
that will be vetting so if I got like
five startups then and there's right now
we're focusing on local and in Dallas
just to start but we might each try one
different vendor and then come back
together and rate them all and then see
if we can get some vendors that we can
that we have signed because you know
advice on finding people is helpful but
to be given a list of validated vendors
I think would be helpful or finding if
there's already a resource that that
does that but I haven't really found it
and and I've actually had horse you know
I've been doing software development for
20 years and managing teams for 15 and I
still had a horror story two years ago
so I don't I think it's mostly random
right now on whether you get a good team
I see so like yeah
we'll sort of teens or developers on a
site look up we're creating a dictionary
of like oh that team is great that team
maybe not so good in these areas so that
you have a listing down
well there's reviews on the sites and
stuff that kind of do that but I just I
what it comes down to though is that
different teams work in good better
different circumstances so if you're a
technical person I'm gonna have any
developers I hire I will be able to
manage more easily than you so for the
non-technical founders you need that
extra project management layer so the
question is which teams their
development processes are mature enough
that a non-technical founder can can hit
the ground running right and which teams
aren't and then there's just just yeah
also a lot of them everyone says they
can do every technology but my problem
was the guy said he knew the tech and
then a couple weeks into it he liked
spent a week doing something that the
tech had built in already done I'm like
I thought you said you knew this tech so
and the realization that you really you
have to meet with him every day you do
have to like one person said I don't
really wanna have to babysit this team
and I'm like well I don't want to either
but they don't know your business and
they don't know what's going on it
really it still takes a lot of time yeah
and then the whole translation thing so
yeah working out those issues I don't
know what super valuable because on a
site like up work I find it's a lot like
let's do something with uber or there's
a real pressure to give somebody five
stars like it's sort of the built in
thing is kind of expected which kind of
makes the five star almost like the
baseline like yeah four star I guess
maybe and then after that you aren't
getting any work and that's true and so
it's kind of trying to find the good
people who actually fill those those
check boxes that you're talking about
like can they work with somebody who's
maybe not an experienced founder who's
led did dev teams are they good at that
part of it and internally without
affecting their score on up work or
wherever are they actually you know are
they actually five stars or is that just
being nice
alright and now today five stars in that
in the specific tech in red sure yeah I
I think that would provide value I don't
know any way I could make money doing it
but but also right now I you know I want
to focus I barely got eighteen hours
working on a recent score last week and
I'd rather have it be 40 so I really
don't want another project I would help
you guys out an hour a week but I don't
want to take on a whole nother thing but
I might just because it's so needed
yeah I mean that sounds like a
incredibly important layer to something
like together tech and possibly even
more at home so if there's any sort of
any online meetings being set up for
something I'd be interested in
participating in that as well yeah and
with yeah with together tech you know at
some point we'll want to be I think the
goal was to be you know raising money
from the people that want to use the
tech and then hiring technical people
and I was hoping I could you know fund
myself a little bit that way but will
need more resources at some point so
having a process that vets technical
resources involvement something we could
actually create that is a labor platform
specifically designed for tech people to
create teams to be able to bet people on
the various skills right like how good
are they at this various software
actually and price accordingly but
created with and for the tech teams like
to be able to actually get people to
work who are bored at home and then also
getting in access to labor that you know
I'm interested to hear what people think
about how is this different or is this
different than like a project trying to
record how a volunteer did it something
right so let's say like as a project
owner I say I really need help with
marketing and so I put it out on
whatever platform and somebody bridges
her hand and says sure I can help and
they do it and as a project owner I'll
get a sense hopefully for like well this
person is great at doing this I felt
like they were a real you know asset to
the team and I wanna keep working with
them as opposed to I'm not sure if they
just didn't get what we were going for
or they're not actually as good at
marketing as they thought they were but
like no thanks I'll keep looking so you
know and that kind of where it helps the
you know if you're a project owner and
you see that somebody who's who's
volunteered has worked on five other
projects and they've all said yeah that
person is good that says one thing or if
the person has no history slash you know
three bad ones you're like mmm maybe you
know have you done
work since then or is there any other
any other areas you want to help with
yeah I don't think there's any
differences between marketing sales and
tact just in all of those areas I think
things need to be broken down on level
detail but because in the the technology
side we might say oh the languages and
the and the frameworks and and the
databases Tom steel but in in marketing
there's you know there's business of
business and business to to consumer and
and then there's also all the different
technologies like I know how to use
HubSpot right and this other person so
yeah there's no difference I think the
reason why the those systems are right
now often focused on different like
either tech or finding admins and stuff
I guess up work actually spans all that
right right to be clear but I hadn't
done but that's super useful I guess my
question is the teams like the the up
work teams trying to go out and you know
look at ten different development teams
and and record how good they are at what
they say they're doing with that same
system be useful so should we use the
exact same system for tracking like the
individual volunteers or you know
possibly even people that we hire I
guess to sort of say like do we want to
track individuals the same way as teams
and have that same sort of a system
regardless if you're paying them or not
yeah I would I would actually always
great on the individual level rather
than on the team level it is an
interesting team re yeah yeah because
you may have somebody who's a rock star
you can't grade on the individual level
because if the team's working on it and
a team creates it unless they're willing
to break it down and even then it's not
necessarily reliable we can know who did
what if it's a very structured task but
not if it's like you track both so you
track like here's the team here's what
kind of the stuff they did it and then
here's the individuals and then you can
start to see like oh look that person
they failed as a part of that team but
they were great as
one of these tenting so like maybe there
just shouldn't be a part of that team or
you know it was a different like
language than they were used to or
whatever it is but yeah you tracked both
levels and then you can start to after a
couple projects learn some stuff from
the data I think having the team's be
we're kind of currently talking about it
where it's we're hiring them right where
the boss and we're deciding do they have
enough stars do they have enough having
it be created from the opposite
direction of we have tens of thousands
of people who want to volunteer how do
they find teams and how do they they
know what they're good at so they can
contribute in that way and so they how
do you help them figure out where they
are five stars or where they have the
most potential for that and have it in a
in a way that isn't you need to be five
stars in these five areas because
otherwise no one's gonna hire you and
instead it's like no we want to know the
truth we want to know where we are good
at so we feel good contributing and
we're a team is gonna work really well
together and we're you know if someone
has a track record as someone who's
possibly putting together a team and
paying them to do to do a project but
then you get it created from this
because otherwise who's gonna come on
board for like oh you're gonna rape me
great that's awesome
Danna I think also be reading has to go
both ways because if I as a project
owner I'm like one star ones too and
everyone's like this guy's an asshole
then people probably should have work
for that project yeah yeah that's all
valid an excellent points jibley we the
things that we have to kind of work
around with that is kind of that
dunning-kruger effect where people tend
to overestimate themselves I know I have
throughout my whole life but that yeah
there's gonna be challenges any
direction you go but I like the idea of
you know that it's a platform to help
people find where they can provide value
and then yeah these titles of software
developer really is meaningless I think
that the more granular you get and say
oh I know I know
javis front-end work right that's the
the more detailed you can get
the better because the rolls are a a
each kind of yeah there might be someone
who can do these two things but maybe it
is a team of two people that have these
skill sets that does the same thing so
really what you need is a conglomeration
of multiple people working together and
their combined kill the skill sets get
that project done but the titles right
now are really too big and now there's a
lot of I do want to caveat this with
that there are a lot of people out that
are kind of tackling this issue I've
heard a couple start up pitches recently
so we definitely don't want to go just
reinventing the wheel and look and see
what's out there but the I'd be
surprised if there's anything out of the
box that worked but is there from that
direction though there's definitely from
the ups work do you you know are you
hiring this person and are they five
stars but not from the how do you help
people find their third good and where
they're needed yeah and help the
volunteer layer which is something that
of course up work is I think I have seen
kind of the volunteer piece but I don't
think I've seen anyone focusing it from
the funded direction of the of the
volunteer or the I don't know how you
use that word other than volunteer slash
employee but the participant as opposed
to the person needing the work done yeah
no I haven't seen that specifically but
a lot of the tools that they're doing
we'd still want to look and learn from
the front of things I think a lot of it
would be researching also just to point
out that that kind of that kind of
research on what's out there that
doesn't have to be a technical person
right any of us that's interested in it
can can do that interested to hear from
Sam and Shiloh Sam I guess it's a
project person in Shiloh is a project
people talking at this level is that
interesting is that off-putting what's
the
for me can you guys hear me um I am NOT
a technical person so there's a lot of
things you're talking about that I don't
know like up work and I mean I can kind
of figure out what you're talking about
I it's still kind of vague and I don't
know I do probably have a lot to add but
I still am feeling everything out and
not sure exactly where to put my energy
I really like what Jubilee was saying
about kind of from the bottom up a
different way than the top down like
reading someone and only these people on
the project or whatever I like the idea
of having this under structure where you
can volunteer in places that fit you but
yet where do you find that so I'm very
much for me I'm a hands-on not online
person I like to I mean if I'm going to
work on a project I want to be able to
physically do something on it I'm
probably not the best person to judge
this but that's my input should be clear
where that's any skill set that will end
up meeting the person who's not online
the first like that's still very viable
insight yeah just to define terms that's
good that you pointed it out shallow cos
sometimes we're using terminology that
not everyone knows but up works a site
where you can hire people for short term
contracts so freelancer hub work
LinkedIn maybe yeah and it's it's global
so like at work I hire people to work on
data from like the Philippines in India
right so that's your like it's
inexpensive data work for stuff that
maybe the company can't justify spending
like a lot of money on but then there's
also like thousand-dollar on our lawyers
and everywhere in between so it's it's
meant to be that a person can sort of
set here's what my skill sets are here's
my rate and then as a person
who's me they work done I can go and
search for someone or post a job and say
I need it's done either you know I'm
paying a thousand dollars or you know I
need this done please send him your
quotes I'll have to check it out and I
kind of missed what Sam's project was he
can summarize it or I can just check
later and watch the video so in a
nutshell it's basically a website to
guide people into the game be space in
an accessible way without using any
jargon or anything and just kind of
switch people on to being a bit more
civic minded and maybe channel that into
some of the communities that we've got
going essentially yeah
all right so I'm just wondering we
talked about the beginning what this
hour could look like and then we went
off on my favorite kind of tangent thing
kind of things that we can create do we
want to in the neck last 20 minutes
actually do a mini mastermind group that
like what that would look like or did we
already introduced our projects it kind
of said what we most of it looked pretty
cool in my opinion
yeah I think we could step through it
again and it might come out a little
different so to reiterate I think
usually a mastermind is closed group so
you don't have to describe your project
each time but since we're doing this
it's an open thing even it might be good
every time to give the one sentence or
two sentence description of your project
which would also be good for us to craft
that and then kind of say either you
know what you've been what you've
accomplished since the last meeting and
maybe what you can accomplish before the
next meeting if you want that
accountability that's not obligatory but
and then if you want to you could also
kind of state a problem and then usually
what we do is even before the meeting
one person the way this format is one
person is kind of designated to bring
their problem and then everyone helps
them work on that problem we could
already kind of say that that's Sam's
project on because that's kind of the
focus of this meeting outside of that so
we might do it that way and just figure
out if Sam needs any next-step help or
if he just wants feedback so yeah that's
the format any questions and then I can
kind of start off okay
we already did our pitches although if
you want to do one sentence one to
practice that'd be good so recent scores
uh actually I don't know which one
sentence I'm gonna give so thank you
because I the problem is mine has like
four or five different uses uses because
it's the base technology so I might give
a different pitch each time there's not
what the one pitch that covers the whole
system is too vague to be meaningful but
the system that helps people agree on
continuous issues it's one of the
systems that does that
and this last week like I said it's been
about 18 hours I rewriting the back end
to give more flexibility so that I can
add new features going forward I was
hoping to be done at the end this week
but I wasn't so by the the next meeting
I hope to have a fully working prototype
on the new back end and maybe some of
the new features that I can go into more
detail but I'll leave it to other people
Sejal maybe you sure so my one sentence
wiki election is a platform that's meant
to fight misinformation in politics
science and news the stuff that I'm
doing now is I do a week or so I get to
bi-weekly live stream on four different
core modules where I cycle through them
to sort of talk about payment in more
detail and kind of hash out my
explanation of them so I've got a slide
deck that I go through and update and
then in alternating topics I'd go
through that part of the slide deck and
explain it in a bit more detail and
figure out what I might want to improve
for next time and last session was
actually awesome because I had somebody
from the game v-space attend as a guest
and just ask a bunch of questions and
that was insanely valuable for me the
next step is during this biz lockdown
working on the sort of first draft of
the specs because as I said I'm not a
coder so my role there is I draft a
document that explains how a coder what
actually build it and and what it needs
to be able to do and then I'll be
putting that on probably of work to
actually get some coding started during
this this lockdown that's my next step
my project is solution raisings which I
which would what is the elevator pitch
in an hour we come up with a actual
adjacent possible solution that we could
accomplish together if we had 10,000
people and $100,000 and what I have been
doing over the last little while is
hosting them we've had six of them and I
am also going live nightly during the
lockdown pandemic to figure out how can
we create that together how can we
crowdsource the crowd how could we
figure out how to involve people in
creating something together that isn't
what we've done so far on the planet
what I so what I'm doing next is hosting
the next solution raising on solution
raisings themselves how can we what have
you been doing what's working what's not
well how can we
prove it and how could we maybe
potentially get 10,000 people and
$100,000 so that is what I am doing and
I don't really have a problem that needs
to get solved because that is the
problem and I think it will be solved
like why knightly going live nightly and
having more and more people join and
having people guest host and just
creating that time kind of like what
we're doing here creating that time for
to be for the public how does the public
engage in ukranian something together I
guess if I can just give you an update
I'm a visual artist I'm currently making
a lot of paintings kind of um in a
symbolic way introducing this new game
be I guess you'd say new system in the
world so I'm always working on my
paintings this week I'm actually working
with a carpenter to make large 4 foot by
5 foot wood panels so I can get some
bigger paintings out there and that's
what I'm working on so and my bigger
goal is to eventually have an art show
where I can introduce these types of
things took a more general public
audience and person instead of just
online so it's just another way to build
more support for this type of system
yeah that sounds great
yes oh I suppose doing this for the
exercise of that right yeah so I suppose
it's a civic onboarding website
essentially and I mean the process
building it hopefully get something live
by the end of next week I'm always kind
of usually open to critique on things
but maybe once I've got the first
iteration that would be a good time to
get that and things can be easily
changed so yeah that's where what - and
it took us I don't know how much time -
when we started but around that to get
to that point and then we'd have the
rest of the hour to concentrate on
solutions on solving the problems that
we each each brought up there was
something else I was gonna say I don't
remember that Lee yeah yeah so yeah
normally at that point hood there would
be the person designated which for this
episode could be Sam or you know you can
always pass and then we could just talk
about which which problem idea which
problem we talked about that affected
most of us or you know we could just
decide at that time what to talk about
and so just kind of go down that path
since we've started with Sam so I guess
the next thing would be out once you
kind of get a an initial yeah so I don't
know how far you want to go before
getting a lot of feedback so that would
be really kind of up to you and then you
know we could share screens on this
and walk through it we could even do
that with the images you provided us on
on Facebook yeah do you mean now or no
time or yeah we could unless anyone else
has a topic we want to go over I think
we have oh we have about ten minutes so
yeah I suppose one kind of issue is that
that may be solved if you guys wanted to
have your projects on there as the you
know start to the database then I'd be
great obviously I don't see in presented
as a database it'd be more like a each
entry would have a an image to represent
it and you know it would be kind of
appealing visually to kind of encourage
people to want to get involved
you're showing appropriate information
based on who who's viewing it uh
basically like if you're a volunteer
you're showed view that's meant for
volunteers so like here's things that
you can do at home your project you can
help with that kind of thing I know what
you're saying
I meant more the top level where people
are just viewing the projects that are
right in existence so I'd imagined it
would be
have you ever seen masonry used on a
website where it's a set of blocks and
then you can click on something and it
will rearrange them to into the category
that you've selected and it'd be like an
image or I think I've seen yeah I think
essentially it'd be like an advert for
the project in a in a square and it'd be
a series of a grid of the different
projects so oh I've got lists of them
essentially I got yeah
so obviously I need to populate that
red with something to begin with so so
we need to answer the questions that you
posted in the game B projects thing yeah
yeah suppose that'd be a good start
assuming you do want to have your
projects on there if you want more
people around essentially and re are you
thinking that your that the website will
be that the code will kind of be listed
somewhere on an open source thing or are
you not taking the time to do that I'm
basically I'm just using plugins so it's
nothing that I've actually coded myself
if that's what you mean
it's a be a WordPress website with a
it's like a directory plug-in that
allows you to sort things into
categories yeah and I even look to see
how easy this is to do WordPress I have
a couple WordPress sites I've managed
but I do very little work on them but I
don't know if you would if it supports
the giving us a login and letting us
maintain that but I think right now
you're just talking about you're gonna
be kind of probably handcrafting of the
page yeah actually there is that feature
and people guest can create their own
things as well I haven't really tried it
out so there may be obviously caveats to
having that fully opened up but yes I
supposed to be in with I was just going
to add things and have it closed
essentially yeah yeah so I think I could
I could go on and put put the answers to
your questions in there and and I don't
know Jubilee if I wasn't I kind of
looked around I couldn't find that
spreadsheet that we posted a while back
I don't know if it's easy for you to
pull up I did not look around so I can
see if I can find the spreadsheet maybe
it's one
I have permission it's maybe on my Drive
spreadsheet or I don't know what's
calling put together the projects yeah
and if so I will send it to Sam
otherwise we will fill out what you
posted in game B projects for our
individual projects yeah that'd be great
I've actually it may be worth me
actually showing you how it may be
presented so gives you an idea and
actually what information should be
shown alongside any entries I don't know
I'll maybe post something like that
maybe a visual of what it may look like
yeah that sounds great
do that because that in projects and I
did have a question before we we go
which we still have seven minutes but
are we doing this next week at 9 a.m. or
2 p.m. I would join back at work what
are we doing you just bought for me you
could do 92 p.m. 9 a.m. 2 p.m. and have
and be 2 p.m. in case you guys are
wondering that helps people in like
Australia and stuff joins well cuz my
name's waters a little bit too early for
that yeah what was at the same time that
does not usually work for people in
Europe right 10 p.m. their time you know
yeah I suppose 9 a.m. it D say it's
probably painful to me but it's probably
flexible yeah what I'm done arguing them
GMT honestly yeah
is this also camping something we
eventually move off of youtube and on to
zoom we have joining during those two
time slots and the idea could be that we
you make either of them but then that
would kind of involve us putting both of
them on not necessarily one person
and has to be it both of them to
facilitate it right I'm having people be
able to come and bring their projects
and do this process right say what
you're doing without looking what we
just did so did I ask a question are we
doing this one week 90 on the other week
you 2 p.m. then going back and forth
that's what we're doing for now right
yeah yeah does that not work for anyone
well the point isn't because the point
is it shouldn't work for everyone right
the point isn't people at both them it's
that like I can do both of them so if
you can do both them you're welcome at
both of them but the idea is you know
that this one's happening every other
week so you come to this one every other
week that is what yeah I'm wondering
because there's so few of us just is
there anyone here that it doesn't work
for more to know who like just
explicitly who we are sort of excluding
by by going to that time yeah is it work
for you Sam can you come when it's at
2:00 p.m. which is in like 4 hours from
now is when it starts be probably quite
difficult actually okay we don't have
anyone else looking to come for 2 p.m.
so we could keep it at 9 a.m. for a few
weeks and then possibly add a second
time when there's enough people at this
one that want to also have it have a
different one yeah we do that I think
that make sense and then sort of give
people like hey if you want a new time
spot and you want to attend we reach out
and we can do a 2:00 p.m. and then maybe
it's not 2:00 p.m. maybe it's a
different a different time that works
for it okay and then people can if
they're rewatching confirmed for an hour
can also say hey I can't come at this
time but I could come if there was a 2
p.m. one right or whatever time works
for you and then that is these sections
we can open up for people who have
projects or any anything they want to
come in and create together
maybe it doesn't fit under the word
projects types anyone have any closing
thoughts for today before we stop no
this was really fun though I'm doing
before but yeah it's a nicely if
everyone's ideas and quite encouraging
I suppose yeah to Shiloh Jubilee you're
doing every evening at 6:00 Pacific
Standard Time you're doing a live video
somewhere yes on the Jubilee saves the
world by meandering through life YouTube
channel every time I say it and yes my
brother was on and we had the course one
last night and my brother was on with me
and so I would love if somebody wants to
join me tonight at 6 p.m. Pacific
Standard Time or do that is it just
YouTube or is it on stream yard or it's
on youtube and periscope he ran through
stream yard yeah so yes youth you just
if I go to your YouTube channel you'll
have a link there yeah yeah I don't know
if I have it up yet but yeah
the ideas are probably also to put them
up more than the day of but I will I
will try to get that that's going to be
there I don't know if I can like I'm
probably gonna be by myself talking
about too much you know the audience for
40 minutes and we'll see we'll see what
happens during that time what is just to
keep showing up and having teach more
and more people join thank you guys yeah
guys bye bye